uh let's start
again we you
[Music]
guys he says
uh Shen when I lose something and others
get something
when this like if someone criticizes
me
then kind of they get something
right the people who criticize you they
want
something and then uh the person who's
criticized which is
me I lost
something and uh we should try to stop
that
feeling when someone criticizes you
because you are going to improve
yourself actually you are the winner
okay uh and then he has a final he has a
final word
here and then we're gonna have a big
change in the
text so I think we've been doing this
text for 11 years 12
years and this morning we're gonna reach
a big
a big section we're gonna finish a big
section and he says look uh when people
criticize
you the
criticizer and the person who's
criticized you're both gonna die
anyway
means all of those years of worrying
about the people criticizing
here it's GNA be like a
dream okay when you die it's like waking
up from a
dream you know you know how the first
few minutes after you wake
up something happened in the dream
someone hurt you in the
dream then for five minutes you're like
wow somebody hurt me you
know then you start to drink your coffee
forget
everything death is like
that okay we all have to
die five minutes after you
die you will forget everybody who
criticize
you you won't remember anything from
this
life
so why are you so
serious you know
I personally I think if you're a
student you should walk around with a
stupid smile all the
time hey someone told me you're are very
stupid and you make a lot of
mistakes
yeah yeah
that's then why worry about
it there there's a in this
teaching which I think was from 1921 I
don't
remember inside the
teaching the
teacher who was one of my teachers
teacher he said
look there will come a day
when every person in this room is dead
already and then all the criticism all
the worry all the problems everyone
gonna there's nobody left to remember
them and now it came
true there's nobody left alive from that
teaching they die one by one
then the last person died nobody
remember who criticize
who then in English we say mark my words
it means I'm going to tell you a true
thing it will happen in this room
also you know they say oh do you
remember that time we went to the alarm
room at Prim
Vera
there was that guy you know he died
yesterday and then then there'll be the
second
one then after like 10 nobody wants to
talk about
it everybody will be
done and all of that worry about the
criticism no one will remember
it all the people who remember are
dead and it's like a
dream and it's like we we will all wake
up in another
place and maybe we remember the
criticism for five minutes or
something then we forget everything we
forget even our closest family member we
forget
everything so don't let somebody's
criticism
waste your
time you just have a little bit of time
here someone called me
stupid I'm like yeah you're right I'm
stupid okay what's
next and then I don't worry about it
just do something
beautiful you don't have time don't
waste your
time just tell them to go
I won't use the word
okay mind you could say thank you very
much and just forget about
them unless there's something true about
what they
said and that part you can try to
improve okay now big
news we reached day 19
I think once a about once a year or
twice a year we reach a new day in the
original
teaching this whole teaching is 24
days when we first started 13 years ago
something 12 years ago
I taught you the last two days
first because that was the two days
about how to
meditate do you remember it was in the
bug bed bug ridden presc
Hotel had bed bugs in there when
when we taught
meditation everybody's
like things have improved so
much yeah so we finished uh day number
we finished two of the of the last
days so actually we there's 24 days
total now we have reached 21
and we're almost
finished why I taught the last part
first that's the part about
meditation and you're supposed to
meditate on all of this
book so I taught the meditation
first if you weren't there in the bed
bugs
time I'm going to repeat that
part
okay from another
book which is the greatest Buddhist book
ever written
in it's calledo the big the big steps to
the
path it's his book is 1,000
Pages 500 100 pages on
emptiness and how to
meditate so that's gonna be
desert and we're gonna do that in about
two
years if G just stop talking about other
stuff uh
traditionally when a teacher in Tibet
starts a new
day
they will review the day
before so we're gonna go through his
review and the first part is
uh this is a ancient
Tantra
by and he
said means try
to block the road to the L
Reaper and we have uh again we have John
Brady's
database 12 million
pages I can find this quotations in
about three
seconds and if you guys go down to the
verse there's the big letters
there's the whole
verse
means I bow down
to I bow down to the mental state of a
body and then he says it can keep you
out of the hell
realm and it can keep you in the higher
birth and it can take you to the city
where there is no getting old or
dying therefore I bow
to I bow to the mental state of a
bod and that's how he's starts his if
you if you don't know the whole verse
you don't understand what he's talking
about so that's why we're lucky to
[Music]
have ah better
CH yeah Kong means every morning k
when we start the
teaching you should ask yourself why why
am I
here what am I trying to
do and you know I I imagine I I was
flying above guara two days
ago and I'm watching all the traffic
right I'm trying to guess how long it
will take us to get to
the
and you can see thousands of cars moving
down the road you
know and then you have to think wh why
am I going to
guara the people in this class today
will all
disappear and the whole city of people
that I was watching from the airplane
will also
disappear
and they will all go to another
place like there was people in guara 100
years ago but they're all
gone and when when you're in the
airplane and you're watching all the
cars you
know you have to remember why are you
why are you coming to
guara oh I want to help all those
people those how many people in how
many
million yeah uh they have no idea what's
coming they try not they try very
carefully not to think about
it but they all have to
die and they all have to go
somewhere and maybe I can
help so I will go to Prim
Vera I will learn how to help
them okay like that so every
day in the morning when we start think
about all the people you want to
help
and you don't understand but you you are
already a great
teacher if you know anything how to
die
you already a very valuable
person because the rest of guar don't
know anything about how to
die okay so every person
here you're a great
teachers we are starting a
university
why uh I went to Princeton
University princ this year they are
number one in the world according to the
American
newspaper but they didn't teach me five
minutes about how to
die
and I have to
die so you should teach me about
that you should have an MB MDA master of
death
[Music]
degree you know how to die
correctly you know so we thought this
new
University it's a real NBA University
better than
Harvard what's that better than
UNAM okay I got a PhD from
UNAM this the oldest university in South
and North America
America here in in Mexico in Mexico uh
but that their University is
better because you can also learn how to
die as you get
NBA so we are combining the
two there's a real NBA program it's real
what do you call you're going to learn
Google analytics and how to sell things
it's a complete MBA University and we
have uh foreign professors we have lots
of American professors
in it will be a real NBA
degree but with also death
specialty how to how how to take care of
the bigger
things okay uh
and he went to what we call the seven
points and there's a structure that we
are going through that you didn't see
because gesla is teaching so
slow but uh we are actually studying uh
this is a lojo
how to develop the good
heart and there are seven Parts show the
seven Parts
again a lot of people taking a cell
phone photo I think they think I'm gonna
give a $100
tomorrow that proves my educational
system
is just in case I give $100
tomorrow let's go through the
seven and I will give a $100
tomorrow to three
people so here they
are these are the Ancient Ancient seven
ideas about lojo or or training your
heart in the good
heart
number one is preliminary
practices uh number two is how to
develop body body State of
Mind number three is how to use problems
as a path to
Enlightenment guess which section we are
in
[Music]
now how to use problems uh to become a
Buddha now part number
four it's a whole summary how you can
practice for the rest of your
life there are 18
meditations they are not very long okay
you can do it in 10 minutes or
something and we're gonna do that in the
last two days
here grandpa has to fly back
to Arizona that night
before my wife is having knee
replacement
I'm the
cook okay so uh but we have we have a
training and the ACI
teachers are gonna teach you number
four it's 18
meditations that I'd like you to do for
the next three
months until we meet together in
November or October
October October November
December no di
October uh we'll be continuing with this
and with also AR emptiness
teachings with medicine Buddha
dessert
okay in October in diamond
mountain from
now up until
then you're gonna do 18
meditations don't worry each one is like
five
minutes and we're gonna learn them on
the last two
days and they are they are number four
here it means for the rest of your life
you can use those
18 and they are very beautiful okay so
you're going to learn them on the last
two
days all right Point number
[Music]
five we're gonna take a
drink I'm trying to drink green drink I
heard it can grow hair I don't
know
mostly in the wrong
[Music]
place I'm taking that comment over like
somebody like somebody else is doing
okay uh number
five how do you know when you reached Lo
when you succeeded in
Lo how do you know that you have this
good heart
what does it feel like okay so that's
number
five number six there's some promises
you can make about good
heart and we will learn those
together then there's some final
advice okay right now so those are the
seven classic loon good heart topics as
we are in the middle of
number
three but if you can give me the seven
tomorrow three people I'll give you 100
bucks I'm trying to make my backpack
lighter for when I walk go
home all right so let's make it easy
number one
preliminary okay we just make it seven
words okay that's $15 a
word number one
preliminary number two actual
practice number three problems as a PA
number
four the eight well let say the 18
meditations for the rest of your
life number
five how do you know when you got the
good
heart number six some commitments you
can
make can just say
commitments number
seven final
advices fines all right I can see the
gentleman from
Santiago Chile Chile he's getting ready
to make more
money I like it oh by the way thanks to
par for the nice
shirt this
is
uh here we go d means don't forget he's
starting a new day of
teaching and he says don't forget uh
this teaching is going in seven
Parts the teacher went over the first
two
again as he started the new day
what were the first two that was a long
time
ago
preliminary practice is that what we
gonna call it actual practice
practic Yeah okay uh Denny
said yeah he said we got to watch this
habit of taking care of ourselves
[Music]
first and we have to watch
this habit we have of not taking care of
other people
first and we have to try to switch
them take care of other people first and
we can relax well you'll get what you
want if you take care of other people
first
uh then it said we covered
Tong where you take other people's
[Music]
problems by the way that's a very sweet
everybody wants you know lots of people
come to me I want to learn Diamond
way I want to learn secret Buddhism
then he says here you want to learn
secret
Buddhism stay after class and clean the
toilet
secretly go to the kitchen and wash the
dishes
secretly that's secret that's real
secret
Buddhism he
about and and he says Don't by the way
he's summarizing the last few
days don't forget this taking and giving
can be a
pranayama so you can do it during your
yoga uh as I get older my my wrists
hurt my wrists
hurt this is one of the pleasures you
have to look forward
to
then all the bones start to
hurt and I I found out for me it's it's
useful I go to the gym
also or I go
swimming and you can mix up your
yoga so I will I will do some walking
machine and then I'll do some yoga
pose
headand and do some
weights and then I will do a
prama and it's fun in the gym everyone's
looking at you you're
going and you can do
this take away other people's
problems give them
happiness and and you can sit there in
the gym and do it on
everybody they just think you're a
strange
guy probably you are
[Music]
a yeah then okay H there's the 11 points
again I don't have to repeat them
because you memorized
them
you were bribed to memorize
[Music]
them if you're interested the 11 points
are summarized here at the beginning of
day number
19 so I went ahead to teach you that we
finished that
already so he says uh all those seven
points and the instructions for
exchanging yourself and others they are
in the
and then he starts to talk about
mandala and he starts to talk about
secret mandalas
okay and there was
a special
mandala called
King
mandala uh King
arii yeah and he says do it like
him and then he doesn't tell you how he
did so we went to John Brady's data
base I got it for
you it's very very
[Music]
long I think it might take another few
months and these are prayers that
ultimately were taken from the Lotus
Cent and
uh I I so I I don't know when I first
met my
teacher 197
74 then uh I went to study with
him and um he went he said uh we're
gonna go
to I'm gonna go learn
English he didn't know English at that
time and some guy paid for him to go
study in Washington
DC Washington and learn English
and uh then I had just come to him to
serve
him and he said you can be my driver and
you can be my
cook and uh we can go to Washington DC
togethering and I have to stay there for
three
months and we stayed in a place called
vihara
Viara this was part of the embassy of
Sri
Lanka Lanka and they had a place for
monks to live
there and so I stayed with him I I
helped to
cook and then the vihara monks they came
here they said is your student a
[Music]
monk then I said no I'm just I just
started Buddhism I don't know
anything and they said you cannot stay
in this building you
[Music]
know then I'm like what am I supposed to
do you
know they said across the street we need
a new microphone you guys uh across the
street there's a new there's a zen zen
uh
Monastery and you can ask them if you
can sleep there
so uh they gave me permission uh they
said you can sleep
here but you have to wake up at three
o' and hit this
drum for like three four
hours you know okay then I said I was
very loyal I said I have to ask my
teacher then this old Japanese man he
said you ask your teacher teacher say no
you don't come
back you can sleep somewhere
else then I I asked my teacher you
know should I get up at 3 o' and
do
he said if you don't do it they're gonna
kick you out
right I said yeah you can see he said do
it then I'm like what am I he said you
can meditate on the alarm room outline
during
the so anyway those are the first
opening lines of the
L for Japanese
people and they have a very deep
meaning and it's a practice that we're
supposed to do
here and we have a
picture it's a library I think you
guys yeah this is the library in
molia uh this is the National Library of
Mongolia so for 75 years they were not
allowed to practice
religion
uh and I think 15,000 monks were killed
in one
day and they the the other people they
buried the
books to hide
them and uh so we went there in
1997 and we start to dig up all the
books you
know and so far we found 300,000
books and that library now now it's very
beautiful the library is very
beautiful and John Brady is there last
week yeah and he takes care of he he he
he fundraises all the
money to save all those books input
them we finished 12 million
Pages it took 35
years very hard work
and uh it's free
online anybody can use
it uh we are about 7%
finished uh I think it will take 350
years I'm hoping John Brady will do his
yoga because he still has to finish
something and there's a ice that we do
in
Al when we go to the
library we do a little
meditation that the work is
finished and we have a little
celebration with
Christmas Chistmas
Christmas say Christmas the it's
Mongolian word Christmas kmas is the
milk from the female
horse and you don't put it in the
refrigerator and it's it rots it
spoils then you drink
it anyway you're not supposed to do
that but we will have a celebration
Advanced
celebration we celebrate the day that we
finished the 300,000
books we celebrate about 300 years ahead
of
time and it's a very cool
practice you have a little
kissmas and then you
meditate
you imagine the whole project is
finished and everything's
online and everything is
translated it will take 700 years to
translate
it okay by the way we have a translation
team 12
translators uh we've been working for
seven years
we
finished about six books
now average 500
pages extremely
difficult we did
2,100 translation
[Music]
classes each one extremely
difficult and grandpa is doing five
hours a day of those
classes and it's too
much because we have to wake up at four
o'clock to do the morning
classes for
Asia Arizona is in the wrong
place it's in
between also just one hour right
then in the evening we have sorry
morning is for Europe evening is for
Asia but we have to do late in the
evening we have to do early in the
morning and it's it's too much even the
young translators are losing their
hair and that's 61 classes in a
row
extremely deep
classes so we have a new
proposal starting in October
Tim I think October yeah uh I I want to
do a new
way I will do once a
week the whole year you see what I
mean then I can
sleep
so we'll do three hours once a
week it'll be Monday Monday
evening okay so time Monday
evening and three hours of very deep
classes and we'll just do it the whole
year and uh there are 12
books four of them are
impossible so I have another
proposal on Monday
night we will do two books which are
possible and one book which is not
possible so there'll be two hours of
difficult class and one hour of
impossible
class
so it'll be Tuesday Morning in
[Music]
Asia and I'll just keep doing it all
year and if we have a program like
this we will interrupt the
program we will do these ancient
books
and something they do in the G
course when I was it's a 25 year course
when I was in the third
year uh my teacher grab
me today you're not going to the third
year
class you're going to the 15th year
class and I'm like are you
sure said he's like he wave his Rosary
you I said oh I'd love to go
then i s in the
back I don't understand one
word for almost two
hours I I didn't understand
anything and then I went home you
know he said how is the
class I said I don't understand one
word what they are talking
about he said great
seeds you know they're going to open in
12 years from
now and they
did okay they did when I reached 15E
class everything was
easy you understand what I'm talking
about yeah so Monday
night is confusion
night and you won't understand
anything but just open your
mind and grandpa will plant
seeds and they will grow after 12
years and it's a beautiful way to
learn so you have to learn how to
relax in the class and you don't know
what the hell is going
on
and there's a certain mental
state like
Lama plant the
seed I don't understand
anything what you're talking about but
I'm I'm open you know that's probably
what happened in my
hair and just be
open and I I I really encourage you to
come to those
classes if you don't have money just
tell Uncle Nick I don't have
money we don't we don't really charge I
mean we charge for the tech
stuff if you don't have money tell Uncle
Nick that Uncle Mike told you you could
come and just just come so anywhere I am
in the
world on Monday
night we will interrupt the program and
we will have three hours of of ancient
books and I encourage you to
come okay uh why I talk about the
library in in the Lo practice in the
good heart
practice
there's a
tradition
sometimes when you do your
meditation pretend that the whole job is
already
finished okay so in the case of
Al Al it's like I put my mind 300 years
ahead
it's and I pretend that 300,000 books
are already already
finished why is John Brady in Mongolia
this
week we got some bad
news he found another
Library they have 300,000 more
books okay and he actually found a
sponsor so it looks like we can start
so the Lotus Sutra
prayer is is uh you pretend you are
already a
Buddha and you pretend everybody in the
room is already a
Buddha one of the first classes I went
to with my teach
teacher it was in uh Manhattan Manhattan
gr
Village and uh it's a part of
manhatt and uh it was a tiny
apartment he taught in an abandoned bank
for a long
time under the Brooklyn
Bridge we put plastic sheets up in the
winter
that was
bad and it was hard to hear him because
it was under the
bridge anyways he said anybody have a
question and and he somebody said yeah I
have a
question he says we're we're all
supposed to practice L Rim until we
become Buddha
right and he said yeah that's why we're
here
and then this guy said well what happens
after
that and we were all like we didn't
think about
that and my teacher said after that the
Buddhist get together and have ACI
programs and they all go sit in the
class and they listen to each other
teach
ACI what's more beautiful than
that so sometimes when you're in this
class it's a it's a tant
practice to imagine everybody's already
Buddha bu and even gas the last person
is also
Buddha and we're just doing teaching
lamin because it's the best thing to
do
even after you finished the
L what Buddhists do after they become
Buddhas is they hang out and have ACI
programs
anyway because it's fun to talk about
this understand so that's a LJ
practice and the teacher at this
point just imagine the whole job is
already
finished Imagine John Brady's 600,000
books are all
inut imagine all the people sitting in
the alarm room are already Buddhist
especially the
kids always do stuff on
time okay so sometimes think like
that sometimes think we all finished
already we already reached Buddha
together just enjoy the
feeling in the
room and then when you get angry at
somebody you can come
back all
right
okay and uh there's a
how we doing on time
ptim okay uh picture
IM not that
one yeah I like this
picture uh this was taken many years ago
when I was in the diamond
business and I I I learned how to cut
diamonds and if you look carefully
between the fingers you can see a raw
diamond and uh when you see this
picture I want you to think about
diamond diamond way
V so Advanced Buddhism or secret
Buddhism the official name
isad Diamond way
the essence of diamond
way is to reach the goal by pretending
you're already
there that's a diamond
way I'll say it
again the essence of the secret teaching
of
Buddhism is here you can see in the
Tibetan it's called de it means pretend
everything's already
finished
pretend everybody's already a
Buddha and that pretending becomes a
path to the actual
thing they say the result becomes the
the
seed the tree becomes the
seed okay pretending everyone in this
room is already a
Buddha is the best way way to reach
that and you know if if you're
interested in V or Diamond
way secret
Buddhism that's the essence of secret
Buddhism pretend it's everything's
finished
already and the person sitting next to
you is already a
Buddha and that's the best way to make
it happen
cool and so when you see a
diamond you have to think about that
when you see Grandpa cutting a
diamond you have to think oh the person
next to me is already
Buddha I'm hanging out with the big
boys all right okay good
uh next
picture then uh celebrate
sometimes you know sometimes I I tell my
wife my dear sweet wife
Veronica I say we're going out to dinner
you
know at the best place it's called mosc
right and she said what's the
why what's the occasion you know
and then uh in your heart you can say
because we're already
Buddhas let's go
celebrate so sometimes I don't know I I
just some of my
friends we just call each other we said
come on drop the books Let's go to the
restaurant let's see how much we can eat
and
drink Grandpa can have three
desserts and we just go you know and we
have a nice you we call so
right and we go out and we have a a
really nice big
dinner you know and that is the
meditation and it's a
celebration sometimes you should go out
for a nice big dinner and celebrate your
Enlightenment like it already
happened and then that becomes a cause
to for the real
thing celebrating that you reached
Enlightenment already is the best way to
make Enlightenment
happen don't do it every day because you
won't study and
meditate I have some friends they said I
love this practice I do it every
day I said twice a
month two days celebrate you reach buddh
Hood 28 days practice to reach Buddha
hood all right don't
forget it's not 28 days celebration and
two days of
meditation two days a
month celebrate as if you're already a
Buddha 28 days a
month do the
work don't confuse
them all
[Music]
right pretend you are already in your
Buddha
body sometimes send light out from your
body as you are eating dessert in the
restaurant imagine those rays of light
from the restaurant while you are eating
the
cheesecake cheesecake touch every person
in guar and they also
become
and each one of those people became a
teacher and their body also
changed and they don't have to die
anymore and then celebrate
hard okay not really twice a month twice
a month
okay okay and you know go out and have a
good
dinner expensive dinner
you want to know the secret
practice okay here's a sweet
word twice a month when you go out to
celebrate that you are already a
Buddha secretly pay the bill of the
table next to
you talk to the
waiter say we're gonna pay for the table
next to
us and please don't tell
them and it's so
beautiful then I told my wife
Veronica like two weeks
ago let's agree before we go to the
restaurant uh we will pay the bill of
the other table who is on our last
time then she said okay let's do
it then we went to
mscc they put us outside the they have a
a special room where they keep all their
wine it fits 23
people and they were having a big
birthday celebration
and it was
full then I look at my wife I'm
[Music]
like I don't know if we have that much
money she said look something like this
you cannot promise you cannot break the
promise you
know so we did it you
know then we didn't go out for a
month
but uh I went back there a few days
ago and the the waer told me they were
so
happy the the good thing
is uh it's very hard to get into that
restaurant
and now I just tell
Ellie
J say I need a reservation
tonight tell them it's Mr
roach Ro they say oh we're full we've
been full for two
weeks then she say it's Mr
roach oh it's okay he can
come then they call their 23 friends
and anyway sometimes uh
celebrate in
advance because one day we will all
become Buddha
right
then why not
celebrate what's that thing where they
take the guy out before the night before
the
marriage bachelor party
you can do like a bachelor
party you can before the marriage you
can have a
[Music]
party all
right last
thing the the Lo
book which is called the seven point Lo
right it's made of short sentences very
short
sentences and the next part is called uh
which we're going to study tomorrow
morning after
the 5:30 Peach Tree
show three three
three okay that's the next part of
the and it refers to this
picture
yeah this is the middle of the Wheel of
Life and uh I have some good
news last week we finished a new book
about the Wheel of
Life uh we trans it took seven
years SU suang
sangi from a beautiful place called city
of the Lions
Singapore singap he finished it it's
525 Pages extremely
difficult and extremely
deep and uh that book will be next
Year's DCI
course so we work about seven years
ahead
and that course will be released
November
2024 but uh in this
Lo we learn how to destroy the middle of
The Wheel of
Life which is called the three
animals can you show it
again yeah and
uh yeah uh we'll learn
tomorrow these three animals represent
your
mind and they are three emotions inside
mind and they create a
circle and uh we're gonna see tomorrow
how to break
it cool cool okay see you
tomorrow